Cameron Ray

Full Stack Software Developer

cameronsray@gmail.com
(601) 942-4333
San Francisco, CA
linkedin.com/in/cameronsray
github.com/upsmancsr | cameronsray.dev

SUMMARY

Full Stack Developer specializing in JavaScript, React, Node, and SQL to build full-stack production applications. 3+ years of experience in mechanical sales engineering and software sales to engineering customers provides a strong foundation for understanding product requirements and customer needs as they relate to software development.

EDUCATION

Lambda School Full-Stack Web DevelopmentJuly 2018 - April 2019

- Wrote production code for Front End and Back End
- Completed 100% of weekly Sprint Challenges
- Utilized Git workflows, agile development, and project management skills to deliver finished products as an individual and team member

University of Mississippi BS, Mechanical Engineering Minors in Math and Spanish May 2015

 Designed mechanical systems for multi-terrain amphibious robot for ASME regional robotics competition

SOFTWARE SKILLS

Proficient

- JavaScript
- HTML/CSS
- React
- Redux
- Node.js
- SQL

Familiar

- Python
- C

SOFTWARE PROJECTS

Use My Tools - Rental Marketplace for Tools

https://usemytoolssf.netlify.com

https://github.com/upsmancsr/Use-My-Tools-CSR

- Developed a web app for users to rent their household tools to neighbors
- Designed and built RESTful Node backend with SQL database to manage data on users, tools, and rentals
- · Built all React front end features for end-to-end rental experience
 - search for tools based on location; request rental dates; pay for rentals; cancel rentals; submit rental rating; live messaging between owner and renter
- Technologies used: React, Node, PostgreSQL, Firestore database, Firebase Auth, Material UI, Google Places API, Stripe API

Chattr - Live Chat for Sales and Customer Service

https://labs10-webchat.netlify.com/

https://github.com/Lambda-School-Labs/labs10-webchat

- Top contributor on 5-person team to build live chat app modeled on Intercom
- Planned and built all database models; built key API endpoints and DB queries; built live chat UI integrated with Socket.io; implemented Stripe subscription billing
- Technologies used: React, Node, PostgreSQL, Socket.io, Stripe API, Firebase Auth, Material UI

LambdaMUD - Multi-User Dungeon Game

https://github.com/upsmancsr/LambdaMUD-Client

• Built out the front end client for a multi-user dungeon game integrated with Python/Django backend; used Pusher Web Sockets for live messages

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Web Developer (Contract)

Lambda Studios I San Francisco, CA I September 2017 - Current

- Refactored existing API endpoints to improve UI/UX of interactive messages sent to users through Facebook Messenger API
- Built React web app for users to browse books and sign up for subscription billing; created API and DB models to handle Stripe payments and track status

Sales Development Representative

Instrumental, Inc. I Los Altos, CA I October 2017 - May 2018

- Expanded sales funnel focused on Hardware Product Development teams
- Identified prospects' manufacturing challenges and communicated with sales and engineering to establish proposal scope and potential integration obstacles

Sales Development Representative

Aviatrix Systems, Inc. I Palo Alto, CA I May 2017 - October 2017

- Created new inbound lead channel by implementing website live chat to engage previously untracked site visitors
- Established expertise in cloud networking product landscape to provide insight to sales reps on deal potential

Sales Engineer

Delta Thermal Solutions, Inc. I Jackson, MS I October 2015 – October 2016

- Designed and specified product system packages for consulting engineers based on thermal, mechanical, and electrical requirements
- · Created competitive bids according to engineering specs for new projects
- Conducted end-user training on booster pumps and hydronic boilers